Guide to the Curt Royston Papers 1987-2000 MSS.259
Fales Library and Special Collections
Curt Royston Papers
1982-2000
Fales Library and Special Collections
Royston, Curt
MSS.259
2.8 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes, 1 record carton, and 1 film can.
10 film reels
1 videocassettes (digital betacam)
1 videocassettes (vhs)
1 videocassettes (u-matic)
The Curt Royston Papers consists of reviews, promotional matierals, transparencies, film, and video recordings relating to Royston's career as a filmmaker. Materials date from 1982 to 2000.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Curt Royston in 2009 and 2014. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2009.259 and 2014.259.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into four series by format.
Series I: Reviews
Series II: Transparencies
Series III: Film
Series IV: Video recordings
Biographical Note
Curt Royston is best known for his proficiency in a variety of media: painting, sculpture, photography, film, and video, and often in combination. His work has been shown extensively throughout the United States and Europe including a 1987 one-man exhibition at the Whitney Museum of American Art.
Related Material at Fales Library and Special Collections
Lisa Fox and Curt Royston Papers (MSS 249).
Scope and Contents
This collection contains reviews, promotional matierals, transparencies, film, and video recordings relating to Curt Royston's career as a filmmaker. Materials date from 1982 to 2000.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Multimedia (Art).; Motion picture producers and directors.; Artists -- United States.; Royston, Curt
- Series I: Reviews and Promotional Material
  - Reviews and Promotional Materials, 1988-91 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Transparencies
  - Transparencies, 1983-88 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Transparencies, 1982-1987 (Box 3, Folder 1-17)
- Series III: Film
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    Conditions Governing Access
    Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - White Shirt Place, undated; ID: 259.0001 (Reel 259.0001)
      Currently unavailable until duplication occurs.
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Gauge: 16mm
      Length: 1858 ft [from orig. metal can label]
    - En Passant, undated; ID: 259.0002 (Box 2, Media ID: 259.0002)
      Length: 695 ft
    - Lookout Below, undated; ID: 259.0003 (Box 2, Media ID: 259.0003)
      Length: 295 ft
    - White Shirt Place (title on print), undated; ID: 259.0004 (Box 2, Media ID: 259.0004)
      Length: 1000 ft
    - Lookout Below -- A Roll, undated; ID: 259.0005 (Box 2, Media ID: 259.0005)
      Length: 300 ft
    - Lookout Below - B Roll, undated; ID: 259.0006 (Box 2, Media ID: 259.0006)
    - Lookout Below - Trk, undated; ID: 259.0007 (Box 2, Media ID: 259.0007)
    - White Shirt Place (title on print), undated; ID: 259.0008 (Box 2, Media ID: 259.0008)
    - En Passant, undated; ID: 259.0009 (Box 2, Media ID: 259.0009)
      Length: 700 ft
    - Day in the Park, undated; ID: 259.0010 (Box 2, Media ID: 259.0010)
      Length: 1[5]0'
- Series IV: Video recordings
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - Downtown Madonna/Curt Royston, September 1, 2000; ID: 259.0011 (Box 2, Media ID: 259.0011)
      Original format: Digital Betacam PAL
      Duration: 16 minutes
    - "Cool Breeze" Curt Royston, undated; ID: 259.0012 (Box 2, Media ID: 259.0012)
      Original format: VHS
      Duration: 3 minutes
    - Curt Royston - Half Light, "Blue Room" Camera #1, November 10, 1987; ID: 259.0013 (Box 2, Media ID: 259.0013)
      Original format: 3/4 Umatic
      Duration: 5 minutes